craftgossip.com 2013-06-02

# CraftGossip.com Privacy Policy | Craft Gossip | CraftGossip.com

## Privacy Statement for CraftGossip.com

**CraftGossip.com** has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: [ CraftGossip.com ](http://www.craftbits.com/)

#### Information Automatically Logged

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information that is for our records only.

#### Cookies

Our Site uses cookies to keep track of your session for logging in purposes. We do not use cookies for any other purpose.

#### Advertisers

We use an outside ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information.

These ad companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to·not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.co.uk/privacy_ads.html).

**Notice Regarding Online Behavioral Advertising.**

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our Web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

#### Registration

Registration is not required to use CraftGossip.com. A newsletter subscription, however, requires you to register your email address for receiving the newsletters. You can opt-out of newsletters by following the unique link provided in the newsletter that is sent to you.

#### Contests

We run contests on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (like email address), and demographic information (like zip code, age, or income level).

Contact information from the contests is used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. Sometimes external brands sponsor such competitions and demographic information about the users entering these competitions may be shared with the sponsors.

#### External Links

This site contains links to other sites. **CraftGossip.com** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

#### Children’s Guidelines

We care about children and understand that they have special privacy needs. Therefore, we have adopted the following privacy policy regarding children:

  1. We will NOT collect, use, or distribute to third parties personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent.
  2. We will NOT give the child access to unmonitored chat rooms, message boards, email accounts, or other services that would give the child the ability to publicly post or otherwise distribute personally identifiable information without prior verifiable parental consent
  3. When verifiable parental consent is not obtained, we will only use the online contact information (such as email) to: 
    1. Respond directly to the child’s request on a one-time basis and not use that information to re-contact the child for other purposes.
    2. Request the name or online contact information of a parent for the purpose of obtaining verifiable parental consent or providing parental notification.
    3. Respond more than once directly to a specific request from a child (such as in the case where a child requests a newsletter subscription) and not used to re-contact the child for other purposes. We will use our best efforts to provide parental notification, which will include the nature and intended use as well as an opportunity for the parent to prevent the use of the information and participation in the activity.
  4. We will NOT entice the child to divulge more information than is needed to participate in any activity, game, or service.
  5. We will provide the parent a description of the specific types of a personally identifiable information collected from their child upon request. We will allow the parent to refuse further use or future online collection of personally identifiable information and provide a way for a parent to obtain any personally identifiable information collected from their child.
  6. We will provide notice to children in age appropriate terms of what personally identifiable information is to be collected.
  7. We will NOT provide any links to Web sites that are unsuitable for children.
  8. We will encourage children to get their parent’s permission before sharing personal information online.

## Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:

* * *
